We validated the first step, which was the gateway configuration.
We are now going to register this gateway on our network server. To complete the registration,
we assume that we are using Semtech packet fowarder, but later in this course will also show a demonstration
with other ones.
For the registration we need 3 information.
First the gateway EUI, then you need a name or an ID and sometimes you need both.
But anyway, these fields are chosen by the user and it just helps the network server to classify your
gateway.
And finally, you also need to specify your region for your frequency plan.
Okay.
The most important information among these is the Gateway EUI.
This is a unique number to identify the gateway, and this number is provided with your gateway when
you buy it.
Sometimes it can be changed, but to be unique, it's often generated thanks to the MAC address of the
network interface associated with a random number.
Anyway, we need to find this gateway
EUI.
First of all, most of the time this gateway EUI is written on the package itself, so you can just copy
it.
If for some reasons it's not given, then you need to dive in the gateway to find it.
So let's go back on a three type of gateway we used previously. For the Strataggem Gateway,
there was an embedded website for the configuration, so I get back to it.
Then I hit the LoRaWAN configuration tab and there it is.
I can copy the Gateway EUI and I can even change it. For the Kerlink
IFemtoCell gateway, I use an ssh client access. I connect to it and I end up on the Linux terminal
to get the Gateway EUI.
I just need to read the right file and here we go.
We can find the same gateway EUI that the one written on the Gateway package.
And if I edit this file then I can even change it.
And finally, with the STM32 LRWAN gateway, I connect through my serial link and right at the beginning I
can find field called Gateway I.D.
I must admit that the name Gateway ID is really confusing because it's not an ID but an EUI.
And again, if we use the right command on our keyboard, then we can change it.
In our case, we'll just leave it like this.
Great.
We now have the get what EUI so we can go on our network server and register the gateway.
Let's go.